At around nine fifty tonight,
今天晚上9点50分左右
the National Tokyo Institute of Microbiology in Nishitama
位于西多摩市的国立东京微生物研究所
was attacked by an armed group.
遭到武装集团袭击
After the criminals killed two security guards,
该武装集团杀害两名警卫之后
they held a researcher captive
挟持一名值班的研究员
and infiltrated the high-security laboratory.
侵入高度安全实验室
A few minutes later, they set off the plastic explosives they planted in the building
并于数分钟后 引爆设置在里面的塑胶炸弹
and escaped.
随即逃逸无踪
The laboratory which was blown up, contained a very dangerous bacteria.
被引爆的实验室里 存放着一种相当危险的细菌
Our speculation is that the bacteria might have been stolen by the criminal group.
我们推测该细菌极有可能已被犯罪集团窃取
A dangerous bacteria?
危险的细菌？
It is a deadly bacteria which has a mortality rate of 80%.
那是种高致死性细菌 一旦感染 致死率高达80％
To date, no cure or treatment is known.
目前没有治疗的方法
Could the explosion cause the bacteria to spread to the surrounding areas?
那些细菌会不会随爆炸的冲击波向外扩散呢？
That's impossible.
那是不可能的
The blast was rather powerful,
当时爆炸的威力非常大
so any remaining bacteria would have been incinerated.
就算有残留细菌 也几乎被燃烧殆尽了
This has already been confirmed by head of the institute.
这已经得到该研究所所长的证实
What's the aim of the criminals?
犯罪集团的目的是什么？
We don't know that yet.
目前还不清楚
However, we cannot exclude the possibility that they might use it to to make biological weapons.
不过 不排除制造生物武器的可能
Therefore we would like your help.
有件事要拜托各位
In order to avoid causing unnecessary panic,
为了不引起无谓的骚动
please only report this as a bombing incident
请各位只就爆炸案进行报道
and keep information regarding the 'bacteria'
而关于“细菌”以及“有可能制造生物武器”等内容
and 'biological weapon' confidential.
请各位予以保密
You mean you want us to suppress the information?
您的意思是要限制报道吗？
Hi, hello.
喂 您好
Minister!
部长
The criminal group has posted their manifesto on the internet.
犯罪集团在网络上发表了他们的犯罪声明
Also, this criminal group...
而且 这个犯罪集团…
They call themselves the 'Akai Shamu Neko'.
自称“红色暹罗猫”
"We, Akai Shamu Neko, attacked the National Tokyo Institute of Microbiology
“我们红色暹罗猫袭击了国立东京微生物研究所
and obtained the deadly bacteria.
成功取得了杀人细菌
We'll make another move in seven days.
七天之内将有新行动
Please wait and see."
请拭目以待”
It appears they have indeed taken the bacteria.
细菌果然被他们盗走了
But wasn't Akai Shamu Neko disbanded ten years ago?
可是红色暹罗猫十年前不就解散了吗？
Minister! There's no need for a news blackout now, right?
部长 这样就不需要限制报道了吧？
I guess so.
算了吧
Great.
好
Today we have with us Chiaki Ota who's a bacteriologist.
今天我们请到了研究细菌的学者太田千秋小姐
Once infected by the bacteria, the initial symptoms would manifest as itchy rashes.
要是被这种细菌感染 首先身体会出现皮疹而发痒
This is something serious.
看样子发生了不得了的事情了
A few days later, the infected individuals will die of organ failure.
几天之后 全身器官会衰竭 随即死亡
This event has been broadcasting since this morning.
从早上开始就一直在播这则新闻
Transmission is primarily through droplets. Children are especially susceptible
感染途径是飞沫传染 小孩子特别容易被感染
and often exhibit symptoms rapidly.
马上就会出现症状
After hearing what she said,
她这么说的
what would you do, little boy Conan?
该怎么办呢 身体变小的柯南弟弟？
Shut up.
少啰嗦
By the way, Hattori.
话说回来 服部
What I feel strange is that...
我觉得奇怪的是…
Why did the criminals blow up the lab?
为什么犯罪集团要炸毁实验室呢？
If they were only going to steal the bacteria, they didn't need to bomb the lab.
如果目的是偷走细菌的话 根本没必要炸毁实验室啊
True.
对啊
By the way, do you know anything about the organization 'Akai Shamu Neko'?
还有 你知道这个叫“红色暹罗猫”的组织吗？
Not really.
不清楚
I only know that they were a terrorist group that used to steal money from big companies decades ago.
我只知道他们是十几年前专偷大财团财产的恐怖分子而已
Yeah, we were both kids at that time.
也对 那时候我们也都只是小孩子而已啊
Ah, sorry...
哎呀 抱歉…
I forgot that you're still a kid now.
我忘了你现在还是小孩子呢
You are so annoying.
你烦不烦啊
Speaking of which, Kudo,
话说回来 工藤
you said that you were going on an airship, right?
你说过要搭飞行船对吧？
The one which flies from Tokyo to Osaka.
从东京飞来大阪的那艘飞行船
Yeah.
对啊
That old man hasn't learn his lesson
那位老爷子还没吸取教训
and has issued another challenge to Kaitou Kid again.
又向怪盗基德发出挑战函
I heard that Kid had already accepted the challenge.
听说那家伙刚刚已经接受挑战了
I guess that old man must be...
我看现在那老爷子…
Damn those despicable Akai Shamu Neko!
可恶 这些该死的红色贼猫
Taking the front page news and replacing the news about the world's best airship
竟然把我费尽心思打造世界第一飞行船的新闻
which I poured my heart and soul into!
硬生生地挤下头版
Thanks to you, my notice of challenge to my nemesis Kaito Kid
而那封发给我的死对头怪盗基德的挑战函
was also completely ignored!
也因此被完全忽视了啊
In that case, Kudo,
既然这样 工藤
you can live at my house.
你到时候再来我家住吧
I'll bring you to that Okonomiyaki place I promised.
我们之前约好要带你去吃大阪什锦烧嘛
Yeah, sure.
嗯 我知道了
Bye.
再见
(Detective Conan The Lost Ship in the Sky)
名侦探柯南 天空的遇难船
I am Shinichi Kudo, the high school detective.
我是高中生侦探 工藤新一
When I was at an amusement park with Ran, my childhood sweetheart,
有一次 我跟青梅竹马的小兰一起到游乐园玩的时候
I witnessed a man in black in the process of doing a suspicious deal.
无意间看到一名黑衣男子正与人进行可疑的交易
As I was paying attention only to what's happening,
由于我太专注于他们交易的情况
I failed to notice that his partner had come up behind me.
没有注意到他们另一名同伙就在我背后
I was forced to take poison.
我被那个男人灌下毒药
When I woke up again,
当我再度清醒的时候
my body had shrunk.
却发现我的身体居然变小了
If the people in black knew that Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
要是让黑衣人知道工藤新一还活在这世上
it would not only pose a threat to my life
不但我的性命会再度受到威胁
but those around me would also be at risk.
更有可能让我周围的人遭受池鱼之殃
Listening to Professor Asaga's advice, I decided to hide my true identity.
我听从阿笠博士的建议 打算就此隐瞒我的身份
When Ran asked for my name,
当小兰问我姓名时 我就编出了“江户川柯南”这个名字
the name Conan Edogawa suddenly hit me.
由于小兰的爸爸是个侦探
In order to get more information about the people in that organization, I moved into Ran's house.
为了收集黑衣组织的相关情报 我便寄宿在小兰家中
He's Jirokichi Suzuki, 72 years old.
他是铃木次郎吉 72岁
Sorry.
不好意思
Thanks a lot.
非常谢谢你
He's the uncle of Ran's friend, Sonoko Suzuki,
他是小兰的好友铃木园子的伯伯
and also a concultant at Suzuki Financial Group.
同时也是铃木财团的顾问
This old man obtained all the medals he wanted to have
获得了全部想要的奖牌
and achieved all of his dreams
实现了所有的梦想 并对此深感自豪的这位老爷爷
but is now obsessed with battling Kid.
现在则执着于与基德的对决
However, my focus right now
可是 我比较在意的是那伙人
are the terrorists who blew up the lab and stole the deadly bacteria.
炸毁研究所 并且盗走危险细菌的恐怖分子
What's their purpose?
他们的目的到底是什么？
Though my body has shrunk, my intelligence is above average.
身体虽然变小 智慧却过于常人
I am the famous detective who can solve all the cases.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
It's the tropical park!
是热带乐园啊
The castle looks so small!
城堡也变小了呢
This is like the theme park in Lilliput.
好像小人国的游乐园哦
What a beautiful view.
这真是胜景啊
Dad, the scenery is great!
爸爸 景色真的很不错啊
Why not come over and take a look?
来这里看嘛
Leave me alone! I'm thinking about some things!
吵死了 我正在想事情啦
Seriously.
真是的
Come to think of it, Mr. Mouri is afraid of heights, right?
我想起来了 毛利先生好像有恐高症吧
I am not!
才不是这样
Does Kid always enjoy views like this?
基德是不是一直都在看这种景色呢？
I'm so jealous of him!
真令人羡慕
But, are you sure Kid will come?
可是啊 基德真的会来吗？
Of course he will.
他会来的啦
Uncle Jirokichi already got a reply from him.
他回复了次郎吉伯伯
Look here.
你看
He no go de o kesimasu.
He no go de o  kesimasu
I say, you can only read hiragana?
我说你啊 只会读平假名怎么行呢？
I can't believe this.
真是的
Listen up.
听好了
I gladly accept your offer to board your airship.
承蒙您招待我搭乘飞行船 我很乐意接受此次邀请
However, I can't bear watching a 72-year-old man
但是 让72岁高龄的老人家在未来6小时内坐立不安
feeling restless in the next 6 hours.
在下实在于心不忍
So, in the evening when the airship enters Osaka,
因此 在飞行船进入大阪市上空的傍晚时分
I'll come to steal the tressure.
我再前来取走宝物
Before that, please enjoy your flight.
在此之前 请尽情享受这趟飞行旅程吧
Kaitou Kid.
怪盗基德
Will you take me away too, Kid-sama!
您是不是也会带我走呢 基德大人
I always found her personality to be quite unique.
我以前就一直觉得她的个性真的很特别呢
I know.
还好啦
By the way, are we the only passengers on board?
话说回来 这次搭乘飞行船的人就只有我们吗？
I remember there's a reporter called Fujioka.
我记得还有一位姓藤冈的记者
That's him!
就是他
He wanted to write about the battle between Uncle Jirokichi and Kid,
他想要全程记录次郎吉伯伯跟基德的对决
so he offered us his services.
就毛遂自荐了
As for the others...
其他人呢…
Well, excuse me.
那个 不好意思
You must be Mr. Mouri.
您是毛利小五郎先生吧
Nice to meet you.
初次见面
I am Masaki Mizukawa from Nichiuri TV.
我是日卖电视台的监督 水川正辉
This is Kasumi Nishitani, our reporter and Ishimoto Junpei, the cameraman.
还有记者西谷霞小姐和摄影师石本顺平先生
It's an honor to meet you.
请多多指教
Hi, hello.
嗯 你们好
This time, our station has been granted an exclusive broadcast
这次 铃木顾问跟基德的对决
of the battle between Consultant Suzuki and Kid.
我们电视台获得了独家采访权
If I'm not mistaken, there is a special program on TV this evening.
我记得是从傍晚开始的特别节目
That's right.
没错
I have planned to ask everyone in the station to work on this
原计划跟之前基德空中步行的那次一样
like they did when Kid performed his mid-air walk.
来个全台总动员
Little did I know that that accident would happen.
没想到却节外生枝
That accident?
节外生枝？
You mean Akai Shamu Neko.
你是指红色暹罗猫啊
Yes, they claimed that they would make a move in seven days.
嗯 他们预告七天之内会有新行动
Now everyone in the station is on high alert.
电视台已启动应急预案 正严阵以待呢
That's right.
的确
According to their manifesto,, today is the last day.
根据预告来看 今天是最后一天
Thanks to them,
正因如此
I couldn't get a permit for the helicopter I wanted to use for my autobiography movie.
我用来拍自传的那架直升机的飞行许可一直无法获准
Those terrorists are a complete nuisance.
真是讨人厌的贼猫啊
Right, Lupin?
对吧 鲁邦？
Uncle Jirokichi.
次郎吉伯伯
Greetings, Consultant Suzuki.
您好 铃木顾问
I'm looking forward to working with you today.
今天就请您多多关照了
Speaking of which, this airship is so luxurious!
话说回来 这艘飞行船还真是豪华啊
And only the three of you are going to do the broadcasting
在这样豪华的飞行船上进行现场直播
on such a luxurious airship?
却只安排3个工作人员而已吗？
Ah... I'm sorry.
啊…不好意思
Because of that incident, we are short-staffed right now.
因为那起案件的关系 电视台实在人手不足呀
Now that you've mentioned it, what do those criminals want the bacteria for?
话说回来 犯罪集团盗取那些细菌到底想干什么呢？
That's right. I heard you can't be saved once you're infected.
对啊 一旦感染不就没救了吗？
I also heard that it spreads through droplets.
而且听说是通过飞沫传染的呢
That's so scary!
真是可怕啊
So the bacteria will spread through cold air?
是因为受寒才传染的啊？
He said through the droplets in the air.
是飞沫传染啦
It means that droplets from coughing or sneezing will get healthy people infected.
就是随着感染者咳嗽打喷嚏或说话时喷出的唾沫星传给健康人
Also, it was said that children are easily infected. So Be careful.
而且听说小孩子特别容易被传染 要小心哦
Don't worry.
不用担心
There's no need to worry about the deadly bacteria.
杀人细菌有什么好怕的
I used to do interviews at a places full of bacteria.
我曾经到存在大量病原菌的地方采访
Look at how healthy I am now.
现在还不是生龙活虎的
Humans are stronger than bacteria.
人类可比细菌强多了
You're right!
说得也是
Then again, little kids like you might just die instantly if you are infected.
不过 像你们这种小鬼一旦感染 应该马上就会死掉吧
Please don't scare the kids by saying things like that.
请不要说那种吓唬小孩子的话
That's right. How could you say that?
对啊 你也太口无遮拦了吧
It's fine.
没关系啦
Don't worry, even if the bacteria is everywhere in Japan
不用担心啦 就算日本到处充斥着那种细菌
we are perfectly safe on this airship. Rest assured!
在这艘飞行船上是绝对安全的 放心好了
That's only when we are on this flight.
只不过仅限于飞行途中吧
Hey, shouldn't we be preparing afternoon tea?
咦 不是应该要准备下午茶了吗？
But before that I'd like to have a smoke. I'll be right back.
不过我先去抽根烟 马上就回来
Are we still not able to identify those terrorists?
还是查不出犯罪分子的身份吗？
Even the key members of the Akai Shamu Neko who are in jail said they know nothing about this.
服刑中的前红色暹罗猫的骨干也都说不知道这件事
The only clue we have now is this ampoule.
目前的线索就只有这个安瓿瓶而已
We didn't find any manufacturers abroad or at home producing this kind of product.
国内外都没有制造这种东西的厂商
It is very likely Akai Shamu Neko made it themselves.
这东西很有可能是红色暹罗猫自己制造的
The ampoule was left in the parking lot outside the lab, which means...
这个安瓿瓶掉在研究所的停车场就表示…
they probably brought a lot of empty ampules into the lab.
他们很有可能带着大量的安瓿瓶进入研究所
Then they put the bacteria in the ampoule and left.
之后将研究所存放的细菌装进安瓿瓶内带走
So, was this ampoule dropped by accident?
那么 这个空的安瓿瓶是不小心掉落的吗？
Yes.
对
It's very hard and dangerous to put the bacteria into these ampoule.
要把细菌装进安瓿瓶里 非常困难也非常危险
We think the terrorists are knowledgable in the field of science.
我们认为犯罪分子具有极其丰富的科学知识
But why did they perform such a dangerous task
可是 他们为什么不直接把细菌带走
instead of keeping the bacteria in its original bottles?
而要用这么危险的方法呢？
Also, why did they resurface after ten years of silence?
况且都已经过了十年了 怎么还会像亡灵般出现呢？
What's their purpose?
他们到底有什么目的？
There are windows here too!
这边也有窗户哦
Those kids look very happy.
那些孩子看起来真的很高兴呢
The fact that they could get on an airship at such a young age
他们小小年纪就可以搭上飞行船
is all thanks to Sonoko.
真的要好好感谢园子呢
They must feel like they are walking on air now.
对他们来说 这就好像在腾云驾雾呢
Nothing, I just remembered something from my childhood.
没事 我只是想起了小时候的事
The first time Ran saw an airship...
小兰第一次看到飞行船在天上飞的时候
Shinichi, this is bad...
新一 不好了…
I saw an UFO. There's an UFO in the sky.
有UFO哦 有UFO在天上飞
UFO?
UFO？
There!
你看
She saw a balloon-like monster flying in the sky
不过是看到气球般的怪物在天上飞
and probably thought it was an UFO because she was scared.
过于惊吓才这么认为的吧
Wow, bragging about your innocent and naive princess again?
哎呀 又在炫耀你那个童心未泯的公主啦？
I'm not bragging...
我才没有炫耀呢…
Anyway, it did show her feminine side.
但是 这已经充分展现出小女生的感觉了
I also hope that this magical ship could fly me
我也想搭着这艘在天空翱翔的魔法之船
to my dreamland above the cloud.
奔向在云端的梦想王国
I'm just joking.
开玩笑的
I figured.
我想也是
Everyone!
各位
Uncle Jirokichi invited everyone to the observation deck.
次郎吉伯伯邀请大家去展望台
We can also see the large gem!
还可以看到大宝石哦
That's great!
太好了
The treasure...
宝物…
All right, do you guys want to see the treasure?
好 你们想看宝物吗？
Yes!
想
Then let's go!
那我们出发吧
Let's go there too.
我们也走吧
Let's hope that she wouldn't be taken to her dreamland by some Peter Pan.
希望她不要被某个彼得潘拐去梦想王国
You should keep your eyes on her.
你要好好地看紧她哦
What are you talking about?
胡说什么啊
Professor.
博士
You have to keep the UFO story
我刚刚讲的UFO的事
a secret from Ran.
不要告诉小兰哦
I know.
我知道了
Is everyone here?
都到齐了吗？
Yeah!
是
In that case, allow me, Asano Mitsuhiro, chief steward of this ship, to bring you to the observation deck.
现在就由我——船长浅野带领各位前往展望台
Awesome!
好棒
There are glass window on all sides!
全都是玻璃耶
We can see the internal structure of the ship!
可以看到飞行船的内部耶
Let's go.
那么出发喽
This is so exciting!
真是令人兴奋啊 请别太惊讶哦
This is Bell Tree the 1st.
这艘“Bell Tree一世”号
It is 246 meters in length with a maximum diameter of 42.2 meters.
全长246米 最大直径42.2米
The ship is one meter longer than the Germany Hindenburg
比起过去德国的“兴登堡”(Hindenburg)号
in length and diameter,
全长跟直径都多出1米
which makes it the largest ship in the world.
可以说是世界上最大的飞行船
Shoot, why is it glass on all sides?
可恶 为什么四周都是玻璃啊
It is equipped with the latest computerized control unit.
飞行船里装备着最新的计算机控制装置
Hey, there are things that look like balloons moving up there.
咦 上面有个像气球的东西在动
They are called airbags which has helium inside.
那个叫做气囊 里面装着氦气
They look like a whale's lungs.
好像鲸鱼的肺哦
It's true! They look like they are alive!
真的 好像活的哦
It's like we are going up in the whale's belly.
我们这样真的像在鲸鱼的肚子里面上升呢
It's so bright!
好亮哦
We can see the sky!
可以看到天空呢
The jewel!
是宝物
This is the place which Consultant Suzuki is the most proud of...
这里是铃木顾问最引以为傲的…
The observation deck.
展望台
Part of the roof could be opened.
屋顶有一部分是可以打开的
You can have a sun bath, stargaze,
可以享受日光浴 也可以瞭望星空
and do all kinds of fun activities here.
能够尽享各式各样的娱乐活动
However, in order to catch that guy, I've set up some traps.
不过这次为了抓到那家伙 设置了一些机关
Let us see the jewel.
让我们看看宝物啦
It's not for you kids to see!
那东西可不是给小孩子看的
What's the big deal?
有什么关系嘛
The answer is no.
不行就是不行
Hey, you!
喂 我说你
I'm talking about you.
我说你啊
Inspector Nakamori?
中森警官？
Mr. Mouri, you are here.
毛利先生 你也过来了
Let me introduce it for you.
我来介绍一下
Wait.
等一下
This is the thing I'm using to lure Kid today.
这个就是引诱基德过来的诱饵
The big jewel -- Lady Sky.
大宝石——天空的贵妇人（Lady Sky）
It's so beautiful!
好漂亮
The blue color looks fantastic.
上面的蓝色真是美到极致
The gem is sparkling with golden light!
宝石上面闪耀着金黄色的光芒呢
Just like the stars!
好像星星一样哦
Don't you find the largest golden grain
那些金黄碎片之中最大的一颗
looking like something?
不觉得像什么吗？
The biggest one?
最大的那一颗吗？
It's like a woman's face!
好像女人的脸哦
That's right! That's the reasoning behind the name "Lady Sky".
没错 这就是“天空的贵妇人”的由来
Plinius, the ancient Roman archeologist
古罗马的考古学家穆拉谬斯
described this gem as a fragment of the starry skies.
将这颗宝石评价为闪耀星星光芒的天空碎片
It is the perfect item to be displayed on the observation deck.
将这颗宝石放在展望台展示再合适不过了
Why did you place such a precious gem in a normal glass case?
这种宝石为什么放在这么普通的玻璃柜里展示呢？
Inspector, can't you see that the glass could deflect bullets even from a machine gun?
警官你难道看不出来那是连机枪的子弹都可以反弹的防弹玻璃
Also, It could only be opened when the fingerprint and the password are both correct.
以及在我的指纹和密码一致的情况下才能打开
Don't you think this system is full proof?
像铜墙铁壁般的装置吗？
That is totally useless.
这种东西根本就没用
The laboratory which was attacked had the same glass case.
之前那个被袭击的研究所也有一样的装置
What would happen if I press this?
把这个按下去会怎样啊？
Try it and you'll know.
你按按看不就知道了
Let's see what would happen if I do this.
如果像这样的话会怎样呢
Dad!
爸爸
They don't have that in their system, do they?
他们的装置可没有这种机关吧
They don't.
算是吧
How dare you do this to me, you brat!
你竟敢这样对我 你这个臭小鬼
Dad...
爸爸…
I see, there's a sensor.
原来如此 是那个感应器
By the way, that's too sensitive.
话说回来 也太敏感了吧
It's true that they didn't have traps like these.
我记得 他们也没有这种机关
But what if that guy did this?
不过 如果那家伙这么做的话该怎么办呢？
If there's a gun at your head, you would have no choice but to open it with your fingerprint, right?
如果他拿枪押着你的话 你也不得不用你的食指打开吧
I don't think that guy would do something like that.
我认为那家伙不会这么做啦
But if that really happens.
但是如果真是那样的话
Inspector Nakamori!
中森警官
In that case, I'll simply do that.
那个时候就这么做
Did he fall into the sea?
该不会掉到海里去了吧
That certainly won't happen.
这怎么可能啊
Damn you! What kind of trap is this?
可恶 这算什么机关啊
Do you still think it's just a normal glass case?
现在你还觉得这是普通的玻璃柜吗？
If I remember...
我记得刚才…
I see. So that's what it is.
原来如此 原来是这样
Anyway, that guy won't show up until the evening.
总言而之 那家伙会在傍晚现身
You don't need to keep a close eye on this place before that, right?
你们没有必要现在就在这里监视吧
We'll make another plan. Let's go!
重新拟定作战计划 走了
Yes!
是
Wow, you've shown me something really interesting.
哎呀 让我看到了有趣的东西
Thanks to you, I could probably write a great report.
托您的福 我应该可以写出不错的报道了
I'm sorry. Please go to the smoking room on B floor to smoke.
真是不好意思 吸烟请到B层的吸烟室
Mr. Mouri, do you want to join me?
毛利先生要不要一起去？
No, I'll go back to my room to take a break.
不了 我要回房间休息一下
My head is spinning right now.
我已经晕头转向了
I guess so.
这么说也对
I feel much better now.
轻松多了
Your father has really been through a lot today.
你爸爸还真是多灾多难呢
By the way, that band-aid doesn't look too bad, right?
对了 那个创可贴还不错吧
That band-aid.
就是那个创可贴啊
You haven't checked it?
你还没看吗？
What did you do to the band-aid?
你该不会在创可贴上动了手脚吧？
Wait, what is it?
等一下 这是什么啊？
Do you like it?
你喜欢吗？
Come on, what are you doing?
真是的 你在干嘛啊
This is bad.
这下不好了
When I got on the ship, I gave a band-aid to one of the staff!
登船的时候 我把这个拿给一名服务员了啦
Hurry up guys!
大家快点
It's dangerous to run too fast, Little Miss.
太着急的话可是很危险的哦 大小姐
Thank you.
谢谢你
Thanks a lot.
真的非常谢谢你
You are welcome.
不客气
You're bleeding.
血
Your elbow is bleeding.
你手肘流血了
Perhaps I grazed my elbow just now...
是刚刚擦破了吗…
Wait a moment.
请等一下
Please use this.
请用这个吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
What should I do? If he thinks that I wrote that...
怎么办啊 要是他认为这是我写的话…
He wouldn't notice.
他不会注意到的啦
The words are so tiny.
字又这么小
Come on...
真是的…
I want to see that gem again.
我想再去看看那颗宝石
There were too many people just now. I couldn't look closely at it.
刚刚人太多 没办法好好欣赏
Well then.
这样啊
I'll go back to my room then.
那我先回房间待着
I promised Makoto that I would text him, but I won't tell him that Kid's coming.
我和阿真约好了要发短信给他 只是基德的事情得保密
See you later.
那待会见喽
Who's that?
是谁呢…
Hello.
你好
Hi, well...
你好 那个…
I'm the waiter of this airship.
我是这艘飞行船的服务员
I' came to have a look at this famous gem during my break.
忙里偷闲 来看看传说中的大宝石
Shoot.
糟糕
I should go back to work now.
该回去工作了
Enjoy your time here.
那请您慢慢参观
Okay.
好
Wait!
等一下
What's wrong?
有什么事吗？
The band-aid...
这个创可贴…
I burnt my arm just now...
刚刚不小心被烫到…
That's a lie.
你骗人
I'm not lying.
我没骗人
Then please look at this band-aid closely.
那你仔细看清楚这个创可贴
Crap...
糟了…
Why would you have the band-aid which I gave to someone else?
为什么我给别人的创可贴会在你这里呢？
You are Kid, right?!
你就是基德吧？
She got me.
被发现了
Tell me the truth!
快从实招来
Shoot, I can't continue my disguise as a waiter anymore...
真是麻烦 看来没办法再继续扮服务员了
Also, if I put up a struggle...
而且 如果勉强抵抗的话…
What's so funny?
有什么好笑的？
Hurry up and confess!
还不快从实招来…
What do you plan to do if I tell you the truth?
如果我据实相告 你打算怎么办呢？
Tell Inspector Nakamori and turn me in?
通知中森警官 然后把我交出去吗？
That sounds like a good solution.
这个倒是很有趣嘛
But, I'm afraid that'll be troublesome for you.
不过 这么一来困扰的可是你啊
You still don't know who I am?
你还不知道吗？ 我到底是谁
That's right. The real identity of Kaitou Kid
没错 怪盗基德的真实身份
is me.
就是我
Are you all right, Conan?
你没事吧 柯南？
Did you catch a cold?
是不是感冒啦？
No I didn't.
不是感冒啦
What's the matter?
你怎么啦？
Have you forgotten my face since it's been so long?
太久没见 你是不是忘记我的长相啦？
You said you are Shinichi?
基德的真实身份是新一？
You've gotta to be kidding me.
不要让我笑破肚皮了
You are good at disguise after all...
反正一定是你最在行的易容术…
It's not a disguise...
不是…
Of course not! This is my face.
这还用说吗？ 这是我的脸啊
Wait, at the time when I made the emergency landing,
不对 之前我开飞机迫降的时候
that "Shinichi" was also pinched by the officer and he didn't expose himself either.
那个“新一”也被警官拉过脸 没有曝光
Perhaps you two look very much alike?
也许你们本来就长得很像？
Damn it, I'm still a bit worried.
可恶 我还是不太放心
That guy always investigate the surroundings before he steals.
那家伙一定会在犯案前来刺探情况的
- Inspector Nakamori! - If we leave the jewel alone...
中森警官 要是离开宝石…
It's too bad you're on this airship where there's no way out.
搭上这艘无处可逃的飞行船算你倒霉
Accept your fate!
你就觉悟吧
This is not an airship.
才不是飞行船呢
It's a UFO.
是UFO才对
I remember you said that when you were a child.
我记得你小时候这么说过吧
I know to you, I'm just a mysterious alien
虽然在你眼中
that showed up on this UFO abruptly.
我现在是突然出现在UFO上并且身份不明的外星人
But I have to pretend to be Kid in order to solve cases.
但怪盗基德是我为了破案而不得已装扮的
The proof is that I always return the gems I stole to their owners.
证据就是 我偷完宝石之后马上就会归还给持有人
But...
可是…
Because...
因为…
As the great detective Shinichi Kudo, how could I let Kid go.
这么华丽的怪盗 名侦探工藤新一怎么会放过呢
And here I thought you would understand.
我还以为你会理解我
Anyway, since it's you who caught me,
不过被你抓住了就没办法了
I have to accept this.
我觉悟了
Shinichi...?
新一…？
What's wrong? What happened?
怎么了 发生什么事了吗？
Nothing
没有…
Did you notice anything strange?
你发现什么情况了吗？
No nothing.
什么事情都没有
I was mistaken. Sorry!
是我搞错了 不好意思
See you!
先告辞了
What is happening?
这是怎么回事？
Shinichi is Kid.
新一居然是基德
So when he said he was busy with cases, he was actually stealing things?
之前他说忙着查案子 其实都是在当小偷吗？
Can you hand me the glass?
帮我拿一下玻璃杯好吗？
What happened to your arm?
你的手臂怎么了啊？
I think a mosquito bit me. It's so itchy.
好像被叮了 好痒哦
Seriously. I didn't realize there were mosquitos at a place like this.
真是的 没想到这种地方还会有蚊子
Here.
来
Thank you.
谢啦
Bye.
再见
I still don't believe you.
我还是不相信
Well, if you'll excuse me.
那么 我先告辞了
Time...
暂停…
Mr. Fujioka?
藤冈先生？
My bad, my bad.
真是失礼了
The karate champion really has strong arm muscles.
不愧是空手道大会的冠军 手臂肌肉真是不错
Guys look! It's an airship!
你们看 是飞行船
It's so big!
好大
It's like a whale!
好像鲸鱼哦
A whale which could fly.
是飞天鲸鱼啊
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
让你们久等了
Fantastic!
好喝
Sis, another glass please!
小姐 再来一杯
Looks like Uncle Mouri has totally recovered.
叔叔完全复活了呢
He even called the waitress 'Sis'.
而且还叫人家“小姐”
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
让你们久等了
Here is your dessert.
这是甜点蛋糕
Thank you...
谢谢…
I've been waiting for this. Looks yummy.
我等了好久了 好好吃的样子
What's in the cream?
夹在奶油中间的是什么啊？
Isn't that blackberry?
这不就是黑莓吗
Ran.
小兰
Why are you staring at him with such a serious look?
干嘛那么严肃地盯着人家看啊？
Is he your type?
那种男人是你的菜啊？
It's nothing like that.
才不是呢
I'm telling your hubby.
我要告诉你老公哦
I said it's nothing like that.
我都说不是了啦
Like I said,
所以说
if we open this door, we could get into the central passage.
如果打开这扇门 就可以从正中间的通道出去
And after that, if we go out through the front door...
再从前面的门出去的话…
It'll work, right?
行得通对吧？
Yes.
没错
Where are you guys going?
你们几个 要去哪里呢？
No... we are planning to play cards in our room.
不是…我们是打算回房间玩扑克牌啦
Looks like they are planning something again.
又在偷偷地计划什么了
I can't wait anymore.
我等不及了
I wish we could arrive at Osaka as soon as possible and meet my dear Kid-sama.
希望能赶快到达大阪 跟我心爱的基德大人见面
Then, after that...
然后 紧接着…
I can kiss those elusive lips of his...
让他那高不可攀的唇吻上我的唇…
No, definitely not!
不行 绝对不行
Kid is a criminal. That's not the right thing to do.
基德可是罪犯啊 这样太随便了
Why are you so worked-up?
你干嘛那么认真啊？
I'm not.
才没有呢
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
You guys should eat quickly!
你们几个 赶快吃完啊
Yes!
是
Inspector Nakamori, slow down.
中森警官 慢慢吃就好了嘛
My guys are guarding the jewel now.
宝物正由我的部下们看着呢
But, maybe Kid has already...
可是 说不定在这个时候基德就…
Thanks for the meal!
我们吃饱了
We'll be playing cards in our room!
那么我们要回房间玩扑克牌了
We'll be going!
我们先走啦
Why are they in such a hurry?
干嘛这么匆忙啊
Thanks.
谢谢
I'm sorry.
对不起
Come on, be careful.
真是的 小心点嘛
You have to cover your mouth when sneezing.
打喷嚏的时候要像这样把嘴巴遮住
Didn't your mom tell you that?
你妈妈没跟你说过吗？
Sorry.
对不起
It's fine.
没关系
Let's go!
我们走吧
(Unknown number)
无来电显示
Who could this be?
到底是谁啊？
Hello?
喂？
We've released the deadly bacteria in the smoking room.
我们在飞行船的吸烟室里散播了杀人细菌
What?
什么？
Are you kidding me?
你在开什么玩笑
Check what's under the couch on your left.
看看左侧沙发的下面吧
Wait a minute!
等一下
What's wrong, uncle?
怎么了吗 伯伯？
Nothing. Just a prank call.
没事 只是一般的恶作剧电话而已
Inspector.
警官
This is...
这个是…
It has to be that.
错不了的
This is the same ampoule which the people who attacked the lab used.
这跟袭击研究所的人所掉落的是同一种安瓿瓶
The information about the ampoule hasn't been made public yet.
有关安瓿瓶的事情还没对外公开
Which means...
也就是说…
The man on the phone is probably telling the truth.
电话里的男人说的事情应该是真的
My guess is that
依我推测
they left an empty bottle in the parking lot on purpose
他们为了让我们确认吸烟室的安瓿瓶是真品
in order to trick us into believing that the ampoule in the smoking room has bacteria inside.
才故意把空安瓿瓶丢在停车场里
Shoot!
可恶
Anyway, I'll report this to my superiors.
总之 向上级报告的事就交给我们吧
You do that.
拜托你了
It seems that the man was telling the truth.
那个男人说的应该是真的
How could that happen?
怎么会这样
I don't have time to catch Kid then.
这样根本就没时间去抓基德了
Seal the smoking room immediately!
马上封锁吸烟室
Also, keep everyone out of the bar too.
连同这个酒吧也一起禁用
Yes!
是
How could this happen?
怎么会这样？
Are you sure?
这是真的吗？
So it wasn't a prank?
不是恶作剧啊
No, unfortunately it's not.
不 很遗憾
We just confirmed it with the head office.
刚刚已经向总局确认过了
Anyway, like what I just said,
总之 就像刚刚说过的
the smoking room on the B floor has been sealed off.
B层的吸烟室已经被封锁了
Help...
救救我…
Rashes?
皮疹？
Is he infected?
难道 他被感染了吗？
Come to think of it, that man has been to the smoking room just now.
这么说来 那位先生刚刚去过吸烟室
Help me... please!
救救我…拜托你们
I feel terrible!
我身体好难受
Calm down! Please calm down!
冷静一点 请你冷静下来
I don't wanna die!
我不想死
Sorry.
不好意思
It's fine.
不会
Ran, you need to disinfect your hands right away.
小兰 你的手要赶快去消毒
This way. We have rubbing alcohol in the pantry.
这边 配膳间有消毒用酒精
Okay.
好
I can't believe someone on this ship was infected.
这艘飞行船上竟然出现了感染者
Has anyone else been to the smoking room?
还有谁去过吸烟室？
Hey, are you all right?
喂 你没事吧？
She has rashes on her right hand and left arm!
她起皮疹了 右手跟左臂
Shoot, she's infected too?
可恶 她也是吗？
Can we find a place to quarantine them?
有没有可以将他们隔离起来的地方呢？
There's a ward in the treatment room.
诊疗室里面有病房
We don't have any doctors onboard, but that place is separated from the main cabin.
虽然这次没有随船医生 不过那边与主舱是可以隔开的
Fine, take them there.
好 马上带他们过去
I'll lead the way.
我来带路
Okay.
是
We better lock this restaurant too, just to be safe.
为了保险起见 这间餐厅最好也封锁起来
Everyone please go to the hall.
那么请各位先到大厅那边去
Dad, get up.
爸爸 快起来
Speaking of which, those children are lucky not to be here.
话说回来 那些孩子不在这里还真是不幸中的万幸啊
Yeah.
嗯
That's right, we have to inform the kids about this too.
对了 要赶快告诉那些孩子这件事情
That's right.
也对
Sorry.
对不起
Oh no.
不好了
This is so interesting.
好有趣哦
I know.
就是说啊
Let's head to the tail of this whale.
接下来去鲸鱼的尾巴吧
Genta, whales don't have tails. It's called a tail fin.
元太 鲸鱼没有尾巴 那叫尾鳍
I see.
是啊
Genta!
元太
Conan.
柯南
Well... we know we are not allowed here.
那个…我们知道这里禁止进入啦
Genta, how are you feeling now?
元太 你感觉还好吧？
He doesn't have rashes. Perhaphs he didn't get infected?
没有出现皮疹 没被传染吗？
Or is it still in the incubation period?
还是说 还在潜伏期吗？
Conan?
柯南？
What's wrong?
你怎么啦？
Hey, let's explore the airship together.
对了 我们一起去飞行船里面探险吧
This is not the time for that. Something serious just happened.
这不是探险的时候 刚刚发生大事了
What happened?
什么大事啊？
Anyway, lets get back to the cabin first.
总之先回客舱去吧
Get down!
快趴下
You guys stay here.
你们乖乖地待在这里
Who is that?
到底是谁？
What is he doing there at a moment like this?
这种时候在那种地方 到底想干嘛？
That sounded like a lock opening.
是开锁的声音
Did he put the bacteria...
难道是他把细菌…
Who is that?
那个人是谁啊？
Kid's partner?
是基德的同伙吗？
Seriously.
真是的
No, that's not Kid's partner.
才不是 应该不是基德的同伙
That person is probably a member of Akai Shamu Neko...
那个人应该是红色暹罗猫的…
Oh no.
糟糕了
This is bad!
这下不好了
Shoot!
糟了
Is that... a bomb?
那个是…炸弹吗？
Get inside.
赶快到里面去
Climb up the ladder by the pillar.
赶快爬上柱子旁边的楼梯
Hurry up!
动作快
Freeze!
不许动
Who are you?
你们是谁？
Did you find the ampoule?
找到安瓿瓶了吗？
Akai Shamu Neko.
红色暹罗猫
We already planted bombs on this ship.
我们已经在这艘船上装设了炸弹
Behave yourself, or we'll blow this place up.
你们只要老实一点乖乖听话 炸弹就不会被引爆
Lupin, quiet!
鲁邦 安静一点
Didn't I tell you to behave yourselves?
我不是叫你们老实一点了吗
How's everything going?
守备进行得如何了？
Cat-F The cockpit is under control.
小猫F 已控制驾驶舱
Cat-D The kitchen is under control.
小猫D 已控制厨房
Cat-C The observation deck is under control.
小猫C 已控制展望台
There's no one in the guest room.
客房里面都没有人
Good. Tell everyone to gather in the dining room with the PA system.
好 马上用广播通知所有人到餐厅集合
Conan, what should we do?
柯南 该怎么办呢？
May I have your attention, please gather in the dining room immediately.
请所有人注意 请各位立刻到餐厅集合
I repeat!
重复一次
Everyone on the ship, please gather in the dining room at once.
请船上所有人立刻到餐厅集合
We, Akai Shamu Neko, have hijacked this airship.
这艘飞行船已经被我们红色暹罗猫劫持了
Please give us your phones.
所有人将手机交出来
Dad, wake up!
爸爸 快起来
I don't have a phone.
我没有手机
It's me.
是我
The ship has been hijacked.
飞行船被劫持了
As I thought.
果然是这样
What are their demands?
他们的要求是什么？
What do you want? Money?
你们的要求是什么 是钱吗？
Or the release of the members of your group.
还是要求释放正被关押的成员？
We have problems with Suzuki Financial Group,
我们跟铃木财团有过节
especially this old man.
尤其是这个老头子
That's right. I did help the police
的确 我十年前协助过警方
destroy your group ten years ago.
为了消灭你们的组织
That's why you should take me as your hostage and let them go.
所以我来当人质 就放过其他人吧
I can't do that.
这样子可不行啊
Why?
为什么啊？
This airship will still fly to Osaka.
飞行船就这样继续飞往大阪
Call the police now.
赶快通知警方
Tell them if they dare to make any moves,
不过要是敢轻举妄动 就引爆飞行船
I'll blow the ship up.
你就这么告诉他们
Also, this is a bottle of that deadly bacteria.
还有 这就是那个杀人细菌
Don't even think that you could catch us.
不要妄想抓住我们哦
If you do that, not only the smoking room,
如果这么做 不只是吸烟室
the whole cabin will be filled with the deadly bacteria.
连整个客舱都会充满杀人细菌的
What should we do, Conan?
该怎么办呢 柯南？
We have to save Ai and everybody else!
我们要救小哀跟大家
The priority now is defusing the bomb.
当务之急是先拆除炸弹
Haibara, one of the hostages might be the accomplice of the criminals.
灰原 那些人质里面很可能有犯人的同伙
You have to be careful.
你要小心
Copy that.
收到
Did anyone of you go to the smoking room?
你们几个该不会去过吸烟室吧？
You did?
你们进去了吗？
Yes, but...
是的 可是…
We only opened the door to take a peek.
我们只打开门偷看而已
The smell of cigarettes was too intense there, so I closed the door right away.
因为烟味很重 马上就关门了
How could this be?
怎么会这样
He came into contact with the droplets from sneezing and went to the smoking room.
不仅是喷嚏 还去过吸烟室
It's all right. We didn't go inside.
没问题的 我们没进里面
Also, we don't have rashes.
而且我们也没出小疹子啊
Let's put it aside first. What should we do about the bomb?
先别管这个 炸弹该怎么办啊？
There are four bombs.
炸弹总共有四枚
Two of them might be near the fuel tank at the back half of that passage.
其中两枚 很有可能在下面那条通道后半段的燃料箱附近
You guys.
你们几个
Can you find those bombs?
可以找出那些炸弹吗？
Of course.
当然可以
But, don't touch the bombs when you find them.
不过 找到的话千万不要乱碰哦
Contact me immediately.
要马上通知我
Got it.
我知道了
Also, if you feel unwell,
还有 要是身体感到任何不适的话
you have to tell me right away.
也要马上跟我说
Okay?
可以吗？
Okay.
好
Ayumi and Mitsuhiko should be fine.
步美跟光彦应该是没问题
But Genta...
可是 元太就…
Damn it.
可恶
I can only pray that he didn't get infected.
只能祈祷他没被传染了
Where are those kids?
那几个孩子呢？
Don't worry. Conan's with them now.
不用担心 有柯南跟着他们
I knew one of the bombs would be behind the wall of the smoking room.
果然 其中一枚在吸烟室的墙后面啊
If they detonate this, the bacteria in the smoking room will spread to the cabin.
只要引爆这枚炸弹 吸烟室里的细菌就可以扩散到船舱内
Next, they only need to open a hole in the airship and the bacteria will spread to the outside world.
接下来只要将飞行船开个洞 细菌就会散播至飞行船外
But, why did the criminals use both the bacteria and bombs?
可是 为什么犯人要同时用细菌跟炸弹呢？
He only needs one of them to hijack an airship.
不管用哪一种 要劫持飞船都不是难事啊
Why?
为什么？
Why are the criminals using both the bacteria and bombs?
为什么那群犯人要同时用细菌跟炸弹呢？
To be safe, I guess.
为了保险起见吧
Anyhow, before they make a specific demand,
无论如何 在他们提出明确的要求之前
we can only sit and wait.
我们也只能静观其变了
Follow the airship, but be careful not to be discovered.
在不被犯人察觉的情况下 追踪飞行船
I'll contact the police in Osaka and all the cities the airship will pass by.
飞行船经过的各县市以及大阪的警方 就由我来联络
Understood.
我知道了
Conan, I found the bomb!
柯南 我找到炸弹了
I found one too!
我也找到了
Okay.
好
There's only one left.
只剩下一枚了
Get down!
快趴下
I'll go find the last one.
我去找最后剩下的那枚
You guys stay here.
你们就待在这里
Open it now.
快打开
Don't try anything funny,
别耍小聪明哦
unless you want the hostages dead.
除非你想让人质死于非命
What are you doing, Mr. Mizukawa?
你在干什么啊 水川先生？
Mr. Mizukawa, did you...
水川先生 难道你也…
I'm fine.
我没事
Mr. Mizukawa.
水川先生
I told you I'm fine.
我说过我没事…
Rash!
皮疹
No, this is just normal hives!
不是 这只是一般的荨麻疹
Come to think of it, you smelled of smoke just now!
这么说的话 刚才你身上有烟味
He has been to the smoking room!
他去过吸烟室
You must have got infected there...
一定在那里…
No!
不是
I did go there, but I wasn't infected!
我是去过 但是我没被传染
Plus, I don't have other symptoms...
而且我其它的地方…
Now's the chance to...
现在可以将那两个人…
subdue them.
制服
Throw him into the smoking room.
把他丢到吸烟室里去
Was I infected too...
该不会连我也…
Found it.
找到了
By the way, where are those kids?
说起来 那些孩子呢？
Kids?
孩子？
Yes.
对
There are three boys and a girl who are at the same age as that girl.
我记得是三个男孩和一个女孩 跟那个女孩差不多大
Go find them.
快去找
Such a big mouth.
真是多嘴
Edogawa, they've found out that you're not with us.
江户川 他们发现你们几个不在这里了
Edogawa...
江户川…
Two men are heading to your direction...
有两个男人正朝你那边过去…
You are very capable.
还挺能干的嘛
You...
你…
What are you doing?!
你在干什么？
Ai, are you all right?
小哀你没事吧？
Shame on you for slapping a child!
竟然打小孩子 真差劲
If try something like that again, I'll kill you.
下次再耍花样的话 就杀了你们
Okay, that's all of them.
好 这样所有炸弹都拆除了
Did you kids do it?
是你们干的吗？
I'm the one who diffused the bombs, not them.
拆炸弹的是我 跟他们没关系
You are bold.
好胆量
Conan.
柯南
Wait.
让我来
Shinichi.
新一
Crap!
可恶
Great!
太好了
Kid?
基德？
Nice catch.
接得漂亮
Kid-sama is awesome!
真不愧是基德大人
He's qualified to be my enemy.
这才够格当我的敌人
Shinichi.
新一
So Kid was here all along.
基德果然混进来了
At least now no one is going to stand in the way.
这么一来就没人碍事了
Go reinstall two bombs.
再去重新装上两枚炸弹
I can't believe he really threw you out of the window.
没想到他竟然把你从窗户丢下来
What are you going to do, famous detective?
该怎么办呢 名侦探？
Are you going to surrender?
就这样投降吗？
No way!
这怎么可能啊
Let's get back to the airship!
现在马上回飞行船去
Don't be rediculous. There's no engine on my hang glider.
别强人所难了 我的滑翔翼又没有装引擎
Consider yourself lucky to be alive.
能活下来你就该偷笑啦
(Aichi Sakushima)
爱知县 佐久岛
It's heading west.
笔直地往西边前进
Are they really heading to Osaka?
目的地果然是大阪吗？
The Police Headquarters in Osaka.
大阪府警察本部
The airship currently passing over Mie-ken.
飞行船目前于三重县上空
If it keeps up this pace, it'll arrive in Osaka in an hour.
这样下去的话 大概一个小时过后就会到达大阪吧
The 'Bell Tree' tower which symbolizes Suzuki Financial Group is in the southern suburb.
在南边郊区 有象征铃木财团的“Bell Tree”塔
Is that their destination?
是这次飞行的终点站吗？
Blowing up the airship by crashing it into the tower...
飞行船直接撞上塔之后自行引爆
Is that what the criminal group which bears a grudge against the Suzuki Group wants?
这就是跟铃木财团有仇的犯罪集团打的主意吗？
That we don't know yet.
这个目前还不清楚
But if it does happen, the bacteria will spread in Osaka.
要是真的发生了 杀人细菌就会扩散至整个大阪
Over 7 million citizens will be in mortal danger.
超过七百万的市民生命就会陷入危险之中
We have to stop them by whatever means.
不论如何都要阻止他们
What should we do?
该怎么办才好呢？
Heiji!
平次
It took you so long.
你们也太慢了吧
Sorry.
抱歉
Who's this child?
这孩子是谁啊？
Hello.
你好
His name is Satoshi Kawaguchi. He's the child of one of my relatives.
他叫川口聪 是亲戚的孩子
His family moved from Yokohama to Nara.
今年春天他们一家从横滨搬到了奈良
He happened to visit my home. So I brought him here.
刚好来我家玩 我就带他一起过来了
Satoshi also said that he wanted to meet you.
小聪也说想见见你
Heiji, you are very close to Conan, so you must like children a lot, right?
平次你跟柯南那么要好 应该是很喜欢小孩子的吧
I guess...
算是吧
I'd appreciate your guidance.
请多指教
Likewise, nice to meet you.
彼此彼此 请多指教
Excuse me, are you two a couple?
不好意思问一下 你们是男女朋友吗？
- You fool. - What are you talking about?
笨蛋 -你在说什么啊
- Heiji is just a childhood friend. - Why do you think I am her boyfriend?
平次只是我的青梅竹马 -我为什么跟她是男女朋友啊？
- He's like a brother to me. - My girlfriend will never be like this.
就像弟弟一样 -我的女朋友绝对不是这样子
- No way...
不可能… -不可能…
If so, can Sister Kazuha be my bride?
那么 我可以娶和叶姐姐当我的新娘吗？
No problem. Marry her if you want.
没关系 我双手奉上 你尽管娶吧
Thanks, Uncle Heiji.
谢谢 平次叔叔
Why did you call me uncle?
你叫谁叔叔啊？
Well, children say what they like. Don't mind them.
哎呀 童言无忌嘛 你就不要计较了
Satoshi, I appreciate that you like me.
小聪 你的好意我就心领了
However, this kind of decision should be made after careful consideration.
不过 结婚这件事要慎重考虑才行哦
Also, if you want to get married...
况且 要结婚的话…
I know. Boys under eighteen can't get married, right?
我知道 男生不到18岁是不能结婚的吧
So if you haven't changed your mind
那么等你18岁了
when you turn eighteen, I'll think about it.
你还是不改心意的话 我会好好考虑的
All right, end of discussion.
好 这个话题就到此结束
Why is it taking the airship so long to get here?
飞行船怎么还不快点来呢？
Before that, there's a battle with Kid.
在这之前 还要跟基德对决呢
The sky above Osaka will be the stage.
以大阪市的天空为舞台
We should get a good view here,
大概从这边就看得到了吧
the VIP seats of the arena.
竞技场的特等席呢
I like Kid a lot. I have to take photos of him.
我超喜欢基德的 一定要拍到他
This is so exciting!
真令人期待啊
Kudo.
工藤
Where are you right now?
你现在在哪里？
Sakushima near Mikawa Bay.
在三河湾的佐久岛
What? Why are you still so far?
什么啊 才到那个地方啊
Can't help it. I was thrown out of the airship.
我也没办法 因为我被丢下来了
You were thrown out?
你被丢下来了？
Actually, Hattori.
其实啊 服部
What did you say?
你说什么？
Are you serious?
这是真的吗？
An airship carrying bombs and the deadly bacteria is heading your way.
飞行船正载着炸弹 杀人细菌跟劫匪往你们那边去
The combination...
这种组合…
is like an Okonomiyaki which has pork, squid and octopus.
就好像是放满猪肉 鱿鱼跟章鱼的豪华大阪什锦烧呢
Two people have been infected.
已被感染的有两个人
Three.
是三个
The director named Mizukawa has rash on his right hand.
那个叫水川的监督 他的右手起了皮疹
That's all. I just wanted to let you know.
就是这样 我想先通知你一声
So, are you all right?
那么 你没事吗？
I'm fine for now.
目前是没事啦
That's the police's helicopter.
那是警方的直升机吧
Are they following the airship?
正在追踪飞行船吗？
Police Department?
警视厅？
Pardon me, I'll call you again.
抱歉 我再打给你
Wait!
等一下
Damn it, he hung up on me again.
可恶 又挂我电话
There's nothing you can do.
这也是没办法的嘛
Maybe that person is eager to go to that great restaurant.
如果有好吃的店 就会想马上跑去吃嘛
Didn't you talk about Okonomiyaki just now?
你不是跟人家在聊什锦烧吗？
Has there been any progress identifying them?
他们的身份调查 有进展了吗？
About that.
关于这个
We looked into the relatives of the crucial members of that organization,
我们从之前组织骨干的近亲中着手调查
but found no one suspicious.
却没有发现可疑人物
Is there no way to solve this?
果然还是不行啊
Hello, this is Megure.
你好 我是目暮
Inspector Megure, I'm Kudo.
目暮警官 我是工藤
Kudo!
工藤啊
I'm in Aichi Sakushima now
我现在在爱知县的佐久岛
and saw the police's helicopter following the airship.
我看到警方的直升机正在追踪飞行船
That's right, Sato and Takagi are in the helicopter.
对 佐藤跟高木他们在上面
Actually, Kudo...
其实 工藤…
I know that the airship was hijacked,
飞行船遭劫的事情我知道
so I have a favor to ask of you, Inspector.
所以我有事情要拜托警官
What is it?
嗯 什么事呢？
Allow me to board that helicopter.
让我工藤新一去搭那架直升机
How are they going to find Shinichi Kudo here?
你说的工藤新一在哪里啊？
You are Shinichi Kudo.
你才是工藤新一吧
That's why I want you to pretend to be me.
所以说啦 我的意思就是要你假扮成我啦
Gosh, I have to pretend to be you again.
真是的 又要扮成你啊
Nothing...
没事…
I can help you, but you can't interfere with my job.
要我帮忙是可以 但是你可不要妨碍我的工作哦
That I can't guarantee.
这我可没办法保证哦
I'll try my best not to.
我会尽量不要妨碍你的啦
Really...
真的么…
Good.
好
Cat-E, you should start the preparation now.
小猫E 差不多该准备了
Copy that.
收到
What is that? What are you going to do?
干嘛 你们要干什么？
Long time no see, Kudo.
好久不见了 工藤
Hello.
你们好
But this is such a big surprise.
可是 真令我吃惊呢
I didn't expect to see Conan here.
没想到柯南也跟你在一起
What were you doing in Sakushima?
你们在佐久岛有事吗？
Let's talk about that later.
这个待会再说
Let's focus on chasing the airship for now.
请尽快追上飞行船
Fly at full speed.
全速飞行
There it is.
发现飞行船了
Please get closer.
请再靠近一点
Please go a bit higher so that we're not discovered.
为了不被犯人发现 请适当提升高度
Roger.
了解
What's the wind direction and the speed of the helicopter?
风向跟直升机的速度是多少？
East-southeast and the speed is 200 km per hour.
风向东南偏东 时速200公里
After you catch up with the airship,
以这种速度追上飞行船之后
please fly at the same speed as the airplane.
就保持跟飞行船相同的速度
Kudo?
工藤？
Kudo, what are you doing?
工藤 你们到底要干什么？
Well, please excuse us now.
那么 我们就在这里先行告退啦
Kid?
基德？
Glider, glider, glider...
滑翔翼 滑翔翼 滑翔翼…
Put the glider away now!
快把滑翔翼收起来
I can't press the button because your body is blocking it!
有你在我没办法按下开关啦
Damn it.
可恶
Where are you touching?
你在摸哪里啊？
Stop it!
快住手
Be quiet! I'll press the button!
安静一点 我来按开关
It's easy for you to say it...
就算这样 你说按就能按得到吗…
Just bear with it!
忍耐一下
That is my...
那边是…
Watch out!
危险
Back up!
快回避
So, Kudo...
这么说来 工藤…
is Kid?
就是基德喽？
Well, good luck.
那么 祝你好运喽
Are you not coming along?
你不去啊？
I'll keep an eye on the situation first.
我先在这里观察一下情况
After all, the leader of the group already got the gem.
毕竟宝石已经落入他们老大手里
Ah, I almost forgot.
啊 对了
Take this.
拿去
What is it?
这是什么？
Jirokichi's fingerprint sticker.
次郎吉的指纹贴纸
Thank you.
谢谢你
I expected that he would use a glass case equipped with fingerprint authentication system,
我虽然猜到他这次会使用需要指纹验证的玻璃柜
but I won't need it anymore. So you can have it.
不过我已经用不上了 就给你吧
By the way, you need to pay more attention to
话说回来 你那最重要的女朋友
that important girlfriend of yours.
要多加留意才行哦
That Fujioka guy grabbed her arms earlier.
她的手臂被那个藤冈抓过
He let go of her right away at that time and she didn't cough or sneeze,
虽然他当时马上就放开了手 她也没有咳嗽或打喷嚏
so I guess she hasn't been infected.
想来应该是没有被传染啦
Just thought I'd tell you this.
但我还是先跟你说一声
Nothing's here.
没有
I thought they would definitely put it back here.
我还以为会在这里重新装上去的
Not here either.
这里也没有
Could it be that they had set the bombs at some other place?
还是说 他们把炸弹重新装在其他什么地方了吗？
In the end, I only found two bombs.
结果 只找到两枚炸弹而已
Also, they were at the same places where Genta and Mitsuhiko found them.
而且 发现的位置都是之前元太跟光彦找到的地方
Why?
为什么？
Why didn't they put the bomb at the place where the bacteria could spread?
为什么不重新装在可以散播细菌的重点位置呢？
Anyhow, I should defuse these bombs first.
总之 先把这些炸弹拆除
Hey, Kudo!
喂 工藤
You said you would call. What took you so long?
之前说会再打给我 怎么一直都没有消息啊
Kudo?
工藤？
No... you are so annoying, Conan.
不…那个 你还真烦啊 柯南
Sorry, I totally forgot.
抱歉啊 我完全忘记了
Come on. Where are you now?
真是的 你现在在哪里？
In the airship.
飞行船里
You already got back?
已经回去啦？
That's fast.
动作还真快
Let's not talk about that. Why did you call me?
先别说这个 有什么事吗？
I'm busy now.
我现在很忙
The criminals already spread the news about the airship via internet.
犯人在网络上公开了飞行船的事
Everyone in Osaka is in a panic.
现在大阪陷入一片恐慌
What?
什么？
People in Osaka are rushing to the West. The station is packed with people.
现在大家都拼命地往大阪西边跑 车站都被挤满了
There's no more seats!
已经没有座位了
But we have few tickets to Tokyo...
往东京方向的还有…
What are you talking about? Why would I go to somewhere dangerous?
说什么呢 怎么可能去那么危险的地方
There's another train coming. Please don't push each other.
后面还有一班列车 请不要再挤过来了
What do you mean? It's obvious there's still space!
什么啊 明明还可以上
Please take the next train.
请搭下一班列车
The highway and streets are also filled with cars heading west.
大阪往西的高速公路跟普通街道也都被车流挤满了
Even the bank clerks and security guards have gone to seek refuge.
连银行的职员跟警卫也都去避难了
If someone wanted to rob the bank, this could be a great opportunity.
如果要抢银行的话 现在正是大好机会哦
They better not do that.
还是不要比较好哦
The anti-theft system nowadays are pretty good.
现在的防盗系统都做得非常完善
I was joking.
我是开玩笑的
The adults are talking. Children should not interrupt.
大人在谈事情 小孩子不要插嘴
Anti-theft system?
防盗系统？
What the hell? Don't scare me like that.
搞什么 吓我一跳
I'll show you something interesting.
给你看个很有趣的事情
Sorry, I'll call you again.
不好意思 我再打给你
Hey!
喂
Damn it, he hung up on me again.
可恶 又挂我电话
What the hell?
搞什么鬼啊
Erm, Sister Kazuha.
那个 和叶姐姐
What's the matter?
什么事？
Who was Uncle Heiji talking to just now?
平次叔叔刚刚在跟谁打电话啊？
It's Conan.
柯南啊
Conan?
柯南？
He's a very clever elementary school student who's about your age.
他是跟小聪你差不多大 头脑非常聪明的小学生
He and Heiji seem to hit it off well.
他好像跟平次非常合得来
-then what did he mean by 'The adults are talking'... - Enough!
那么“大人在谈事情”是… -够啦
You talk too much.
不要多嘴
All right, I'm sorry,
好啦 真是不好意思
Uncle Heiji.
平次叔叔
What's the interesting thing you want me to see?
“有趣的事情”到底是什么啊？
Smoke flares. What is going on here?
发烟筒 这是怎么回事啊？
Nara Prefecture is behind that mountain.
越过那座山就是奈良了
If the people there saw smoke rising from the airship,
要是冒着烟的飞行船被奈良的人看到
they would definitely be surprised.
他们一定会大吃一惊的吧
Not only surprised, they would panic.
不只是吃惊 还会造成恐慌
Panic?
恐慌？
Those criminals already posted online about the bacteria and the bombs.
那些人已经在网络上公开了细菌跟炸弹的事
Everyone in the city should be evacuating as we speak.
现在城里的人应该都去避难了
If that's the situation in Nara Perfreture,
如果奈良变成那样的话
thieves would have a great opportunity to commit crime.
对小偷来说 可是个大好时机呢
You fool, even if there's no one in the city,
笨蛋 就算没有人
the anti-theft system...
现在的防盗系统…
Anti-theft system?
防盗系统？
Is that why... they chose Nara Prefecture?
难道说…所以才选在奈良
Maybe.
也许吧
But... even so,
可是…就算是这样
why did they... take the bacteria away for that?
为什么那伙人…要为这种事而夺取细菌呢？
I see.
原来如此
Okay, I understand.
好 我知道了
I have it covered.
包在我身上
Where are you going, Heiji?
你要去哪里 平次？
Nara.
奈良
Nara?
奈良？
Is it because of that airship?
难道是因为那艘飞行船的关系？
It's very dangerous, so you guys can't come with me.
很危险 你们可不要跟来哦
Please take me with you!
请带我一起去
Are you nuts? I said you can't come with me.
笨蛋 我刚才说了不要跟来
I'm know the way around Nara. I could be of help!
奈良的路我熟悉 一定可以帮上忙的
I'm going too!
我也要去
You too?
怎么连你也这么说啊
Also, I can't take you two on the motorcycle because it's illegal.
况且 摩托三载是违法的
Don't worry.
没问题…
I have a great idea!
我想到一个好方法了
Hold on tight!
要好好抓紧我哦
I know!
我知道
Satoshi, are you all right?
小聪 你还好吧？
I'm fine.
没问题的
We'll be there in a minute. Just hang in there.
马上就到了 你就稍微忍耐一下哦
I just don't feel right doing this...
这样做还是不太好吧…
How... why?
怎么会…为什么？
Ran?
小兰？
Ran.
小兰
Ran...
小兰…
Sit down!
给我坐好
Ran.
小兰
Rash.
皮疹
Help me, please!
救救我 拜托你
Let go!
放手
Come here, get in!
过来 你也给我进去
Don't touch me!
不要碰我
Shoot.
可恶
What does this mean?
这是怎么回事？
Kid said that Ran was only touched, so she shouldn't get infected.
照基德所说只是碰到手臂而已 应该是不会被传染的
Ran even pushed him away instantly.
小兰也马上推开他了
Also, Mr. Fujioka didn't cough or sneeze.
藤冈先生没有咳嗽也没有打喷嚏
Compared to that, Genta was sneezed on
跟这个比起来 元太被别人当面打喷嚏
and even breathed in the air in the smoking room. Yet he didn't get infected.
还吸进了吸烟室的细菌却没被感染
Why?
为什么呢？
The director named Mizukawa also had a rash on his right hand.
那个叫水川的监督 右手起了皮疹
Is it possible that...
该不会是…
The airship is going to crash!
飞行船要掉下来了
The bacteria... the bacteria is going to spread!
细菌…细菌要扩散过来了
And the bombs are going to explode!
还会有炸弹爆炸啊
(Goufuku Temple) Is everybody out?
豪福寺 人都出来了吗？
Hurry up and evacuate!
快啊 快点去避难吧
But what about the Buddhist Statue...
但是佛像…
The statues wouldn't be infected.
佛像不会被传染的
Please get in the bus!
拜托快点上车吧
- What if we anger the heavens? - We'll come back when it's safe!
如果遭到天谴怎么办啊 -到时候再回来就好了啦
Just get in the bus!
不论如何先上车啦
Ran...
小兰…
Sister Ran...
小兰姐姐…
Go have a look.
快去看看
Yes.
是
You are...
你是…
Cat-A.
小猫A
Cat-A, what's wrong?
小猫A怎么了？
Answer me.
快回答
Go check on him.
你去看看情况
Yes!
是
Hey, what's the matter with you?
喂 你怎么了？
He fell asleep?
睡着了啊？
Cat-B.
小猫B
What happened?
怎么了？
What happened, Cat-B?
发生什么事了 小猫B
Cat-B is out cold on the roof.
小猫B他在屋顶上躺平了
Which is strange, considering cats never land on their backs.
真是奇怪啊 小猫明明不会后背着地的
It's Conan.
是柯南
He's back.
他回来了
Kid must be here too, right?
跟基德在一起吗？
Kid is not here.
没有基德啦
Damn it! Cat C D E.
可恶 小猫C D E
Go get that boy!
快去抓那个小鬼
No.
不对
Once you find him, kill him!
是把他就地解决
Roger.
收到
You go guard the restaurant.
你去监视餐厅
Cat F.
小猫F
Copy.
收到
I'll go over after switching it to autopilot.
切换成自动驾驶模式之后 马上就赶过去
Damn it!
可恶
The boy is on the observation deck!
那个小鬼在展望台
One and...
1跟…
The trap which was set up for Kid came in handy.
对付基德用的机关 没想到派得上用场
And this thing too.
还有这个也是
Wait.
等一下
Did that guy give this to me so that I could use it on this...
那家伙是为了让我使用这个机关才故意把这个给我的吗…
Freeze!
不准动
Throw it away.
把那个丢了
Put your hands up.
手就这样一直举着
I saw everything. You sure caused us a lot of trouble.
我看到了 你让我们吃了不少苦头嘛
Now put your hands on that!
快点把手放上去
Can I refuse?
不放不行吗？
Don't try to bargain with me.
不要讨价还价
Fine.
好吧
I'm not like the others...
我可不像其他人…
I tried to warn you.
我早就说了吧
Damn you!
可恶
You've got to be kidding me.
真的假的啊
What are these?
这些是什么啊？
The third trap which Mr. Jirokichi set up to deal with you.
次郎吉老爷爷为了对付你所设置的第三道机关啊
I see.
这样啊
If I tried to get away through the glass windows after I get the gem
当我拿到宝石之后 想要从玻璃窗逃走
and tried to use the grappling hook...
拿出绳索枪击发的话…
Good thing I didn't do that.
真是好险
That old man has done a marvelous job.
这老头子真是了不起
By the way, you've been watching from above this whole time?
话说回来 你一直都在上面看戏啊？
Take this!
接我这招
You're good.
真厉害
This is the medal for a warrior.
这是战士的勋章
It hurts...
好痛…
Can the rest of you hear this?
剩下的人听得到吗？
Your leader has been taken down,
你们的老大被干掉了
so were the other three.
其他三个人也一样
What?
什么？
Cut the crap!
少胡说了
Go, Lupin!
上啊 鲁邦
We did it!
太好了
Don't run around with such a dangerous thing.
不要带着这种危险的东西到处晃啦
Edogawa.
江户川
The two criminals here has been taken care of.
这边的两个人也都处理好了
Roger that.
收到
So many phone records,
通话记录还真多啊
and all this within the last few hours.
而且是集中在这两三个小时里
Who were you talking to?
你是在跟谁通电话啊？
You made a lot of phone calls.
还打那么多次
If you don't answer my question...
你要是不回答的话
What are you planning to do with that?
你打算拿那个做什么？
If you don't tell the truth, I'll spill it on your body.
你要是不从实招来 我就把里面的东西倒在你身上
Whatever.
随便你
All right, put it down slowly.
好 一起慢慢放
Slowly.
慢慢来
I see. What a thorough plan.
原来如此 你们的计划真是周全啊
The attack on the airship is just a distraction.
利用飞行船来个调虎离山之计
Your real aim is getting everyone to seek refuge
其实真正的目的是让大家都去避难
so that you could steal all the national-protected Buddha statues in the empty temple.
再从空无一人的寺庙将所有国宝级佛像一次偷个精光
That's because the security system in the temple is weak.
因为寺庙里面没办法设防盗系统嘛
After all, no one would think that someone would steal Buddha statues.
毕竟一般来说 很难想象会有人能来偷佛像
You lot will surely receive divine punishment.
你们真的会遭天谴的
What the hell are you talking about?
你们在说什么啊？
We are doing this to protect the Buddha statues...
我们是为了保护佛像才…
If that's the case, name one inspector from Nara Prefecture.
既然这样 你就随便说一个奈良县警官的名字来听听看啊
Well...
这个嘛…
Come on, you can't even tell me one name?
什么嘛 你连一个都说不出来啊
As a police officer, don't you find that strange?
你自己就是一个警察 说不出来太奇怪了
There's one. An inspector whose name take on Nara characteristics.
不是就有一个人吗 他的名字非常有奈良的地方特色哦
They are just kids.
对方只是小鬼
Let's finish them.
干掉他们
Sorry, what did you just say?
对不起啊 你们刚刚说什么？
He said, "They are just kids."
他说“对方只是小鬼”
Did you really say that?
真这样说的？
Are they fools?
那些人是笨蛋吗？
That's for sure.
就是说啊
If we're here to catch thieves, why would we come here on our own?
既然要抓小偷 怎么可能只有我们三个人来呢？
What?
什么？
Damn it!
可恶
I am Shikatsuno Tsuyoshi, an inspector from Nara Prefecture Police - 3rd Division.
注：每年十月份，奈良会举行一个传统活动，活动的主题“鹿角”也成为了奈良的标志 本人是奈良县警局搜查三课的警官 鹿角刚士
Remember this,
给我好好地记住
don't ever underestimate the Nara police force!
可不要小看奈良的警察啊
Kudo, the guys who tried to steal the Buddha statues were arrested.
工藤 那些想偷佛像的家伙都被逮捕了
Of course, the monks are all fine.
当然 寺庙的住持等人全都没事
I see.
我知道了
Thanks, Brother Heiji.
谢谢你 平次哥哥
What?
什么啊？
That detective boy in Osaka also interfered with this?
那个大阪侦探小鬼果然也和这事有一腿啊
What do you mean by 'interfered with this'?
说什么“有一腿”啊
Oh yeah.
对了
Here, please take this.
来 这个
Thank you, little boy.
不好意思了 小鬼头
Forget about this. We should send Ran to the hospital immediately!
先不管这个了 要赶快将小兰送医啊
Yes, about that...
对了 关于这件事…
I don't wanna die.
我还不想死
I don't wanna die...
不想死…
Sister Ran.
小兰姐姐
Conan!
柯南
No, don't come over, Conan!
不行 不要过来 柯南
It's fine, Sister Ran.
没问题的 小兰姐姐
Because no one's infected by the bacteria.
因为根本就没有人被细菌感染啊
But I have rashes on my body.
可是 身上的皮疹…
The rash is a result of an allergic reaction.
那些皮疹只是单纯的过敏反应
You're probably allergic to lacquer.
应该是对生漆过敏
Lacquer?
生漆？
The person who brought you here earlier
刚刚带小兰姐姐进来的人
is the same one who took Mr. Mizukawa here, right?
也是之前带水川先生进来的那个人对吧
Yeah...
对…
I knew it.
我就知道
He's the only one among them who's not allergic to lacquer.
在所有人里面 只有他对生漆有抵抗力
Since his fingernails are black,
因为他的指甲是黑的
perhaps he used to work with lacquer in the past.
他以前应该是做过生漆木工之类的工作吧
In other words, those criminals never stole the bacteria in the first place.
也就是说 打从一开始那些犯人就没把细菌偷走
They only blew up the lab
只是引爆实验室
to make their biochemical terrorist act seem real.
让这次的生化恐怖行动看起来更加逼真而已
The proof is this ampoule.
证据就是这个安瓿瓶
I wanted to open it in front of their leader at that time,
当时我想在那个老大面前把这个打开
but he seemed pretty calm.
那个老大却一脸镇定 一点都不害怕
If it's a bottle of bacteria,
如果里面装的是真的细菌的话
he would've tried his hardest to stop me
他一定会拼命阻止才对吧
like how you acted just now.
就像小兰姐姐刚刚对我大喊一样
Conan...
柯南…
Am I right, Uncle?
没错吧 叔叔
Are you all right, Ran?
你没事吧 小兰？
Also, look.
而且啊 你看
Other than the rash that initially appeared,
除了一开始出现皮疹的部位之外
there's also rash on your palms, the inside of your elbows, and the back of your thighs, right?
手心跟手肘内侧 还有大腿后侧都出现了皮疹吧
You are right.
真的假的？
The criminals must have sprayed lacquer on every surface of this room.
一定是那些犯人在房间的每个角落都喷上了生漆
Be it the walls, the sofa, and the door handles.
不管是墙壁还是沙发 或是门把手
That's why other than the rash on your arms which were caused by Mr. Fujioka,
所以 小兰姐姐除了被藤冈先生碰过的手臂处出现皮疹
other parts of your skin that came into contact with the lacquer in this room would also develop a rash...
在这个房间接触到生漆的其他部位也会出现皮疹…
Wait, if that's the case then why did that person...
等一下 既然这样那个人为什么…
Could it be that...
难道说…
What happened?
怎么了？
Conan...
柯南…
This is bad!
糟糕了
With the help from Nara prefecture police, we already know the identities of the criminals that hijacked the airship.
据奈良警方通报 我们已经掌握了挟持飞行船的犯人身份
They appear to be mercenaries in foreign countries.
据说他们在海外当过雇佣军
Mercenaries?
雇佣军…是吗？
So, Akai Shamu Neko...
那么 红色暹罗猫…
They have nothing to do with that organization.
完全没有关系
They merely used the name of a terrorist group
他们冒用恐怖集团的名义
to cover their intentions of stealing the Buddha statues.
只是为了掩饰他们窃取佛像的真正目的
And, the one who paid them is...
而且 花钱雇用他们的就是…
Hold it right there.
等一下
How could you leave your subordinates behind and flee on your own?
你竟然想丢下部下 一个人逃跑
Don't you find yourself despicable?
不觉得很卑鄙吗？
The head of the criminal group,
劫持集团的首脑
Mr. Takamichi Fujioka.
藤冈隆道先生
Boy, I can't believe you figured out my identity.
小鬼 你居然能够识破我的真实身份啊
No.
不
I was totally fooled by you when you pretended to be the first one who got infected.
当初你假装第一个感染者的时候 我完全被你骗了
If I'm correct, after the airship took off,
依我推测 飞行船一起飞的时候
your female subordinate quickly sprayed the smoking room with lacquer
那名女部下就马上去吸烟室给每个角落都喷上生漆
and placed the ampoule there.
并且放置安瓿瓶吧
Of course, she was acting under your instructions.
当然 是受你的指示
After that, you touched the lacquer on purpose in the smoking room
在那之后 你进吸烟室故意去碰生漆
in order to trick us into believing that you got infected.
让我们相信你被感染了
That's why you invited Uncle Mouri to smoke when we were at the observation deck.
在展望台 你邀请毛利叔叔去吸烟室也是这个目的
Mr. Mouri, do you want to join me?
毛利先生要不要也一起去呢？
You grabbed Ran's arms for the same reason.
抓住小兰的手臂也是一样
You plan was to "infect" the people who could pose a threat
将所有可能造成妨碍的人都变成感染者
to restrict their freedom of movement.
就是为了让他们无法行动
However, your plan didn't work well with Uncle Mouri.
不过 叔叔那边进行得不是很顺利
So you slipped some sleeping pills in his beer, right?
所以你在叔叔喝的啤酒里面下了安眠药对吧？
Thanks to you, he had a very sound sleep.
托你的福 直到刚才他都睡得很熟呢
Mr. Mizukawa and the waitress have rashes on their palms and the inside of their arms,
水川先生跟女服务员出现皮疹的部位是手心跟手臂内侧
which means they must have touched something in the smoking room.
一定是在吸烟室碰到了什么东西
However, Genta only took a look at the smoking room and didn't touch anything,
而元太只是看了一下吸烟室 并没有碰任何东西
so he didn't develop rashes.
所以没有出现皮疹
That's why you were the odd one out
所以只有你比较奇怪
who got rashes on places which couldn't touch the lacquer.
脸部跟颈部这些很难碰到东西的部位都出现皮疹
Not only that, the leader had been on the phone with somebody.
而且 那个老大一直在跟某个人通电话
Then I realized that
所以我才知道
you used lacquer in the smoking room to get rashes.
你先利用吸烟室的生漆 让身体出现皮疹
Then you pretended to lose control to get yourself isolated.
再假装行为失控 让自己被隔离起来
Then you could give orders to the criminal group without being noticed.
这样就可以在避人耳目的情况下 对恐怖集团下达指令
You were the one behind everything!
你才是幕后首脑吧
Boy, what a brilliant deduction.
小鬼 你的推理真是精彩啊
However, you missed a very important part.
不过 你漏掉了非常重要的部分哦
What?
什么？
First, I'm not planning to escape alone.
第一点 我并没有打算自己一个人逃跑
Unfortunately, all your substitutes were already...
很不巧 你的所有部下都已经…
I'm not talking about them.
我不是在说他们
Not the ones I hired,
不是那些用钱雇来的部下
but my original subordinates.
而是我本来的部下
Don't tell me there are others...
难道说还有其他人…
Don't move!
不准动
Sonoko!
园子
Didn't he say not to move?
不是说不准动了吗？
Edogawa, they have two more accomplices.
江户川 还有两个人
The cameraman and the reporter both work with them.
摄影师跟记者都是他们的同伙
Damn it.
可恶
Second, I didn't come here to escape.
第二点 我来这里并不是为了逃跑
I wanted to draw you out.
而是为了引你现身
What?
什么？
Do you know why the purpose of hijacking the airship was stealing the statues and not money?
你知道为什么我们劫持飞行船目的不是钱而是佛像吗？
In the age of information, money is easily traced.
在这个资讯发达的社会 钱的流向很快就会被查出来
However, stealing the Buddha statues is safer and less conspicuous.
相比之下 选择无价的佛像反而更安全更隐蔽
Japanese Buddha statues are very popular among foreign customers.
日本的佛像在国外可是很受欢迎的
We were about to find a buyer already.
马上就找到买家了
Now that you've ruined my plan, allow me to return the favor!
既然你挡我的财路 不好好回报你怎么行呢
There's still a lot of time. Let me enjoy this.
时间还很多 让我好好地享受吧
Hattori, you did a great job!
服部 你立下大功了呢
That boy should take all the credit.
功劳都是那个小鬼的
Let's not talk about this now. Can we catch up with the airship?
先别管这个 可以追上那艘飞行船吗？
I haven't been able to contact him from a while ago.
我从刚刚就联络不上那个小鬼
I have a bad feeling.
我有不祥的预感
I see.
我知道了
Listen, Satoshi.
听好了 小聪
You should go back now.
你现在就回去吧
But...
可是…
I know. Thanks to you the Buddha statues weren't stolen.
我知道 这次是多亏了你才保住佛像
Uncle Heiji!
平次叔叔
I think those thieves are targeting the Goufuku Temple.
那些小偷的目标 我觉得是豪福寺哦
There are a lot of national treasure.
那边有很多国宝
Okay, I see!
好 我知道了
If so, just let me go with you...
既然这样 就让我一起去…
No!
不行
It's too dangerous.
太危险了
You have to go back with Sister Kazuha.
你就跟和叶姐姐一起回去吧
Satoshi, let's go back, OK?
小聪 我们回去吧 好不好？
Your mom's worried about you.
你妈妈很担心你哦
I know.
我知道了
But you have to make it up to me by introducing Conan to me next time.
不过 作为补偿 下次你要让我见见柯南
Uncle Heiji, he's the one you are going to rescue, right?
平次叔叔你要去救那个小孩吧
Okay, deal.
我知道了 就这么说定了
Kazuha, please take care of him.
和叶 接下来就拜托你了
Count on me.
包在我身上
Heiji, you should be careful too.
平次你也要小心啊
Okay, let's go!
好 我们出发吧
Oh...
哦…
I can't believe you guys are with them.
没想到你们跟他们是一伙的
Everything's settled over there.
那边也OK了
Hey, untie us!
喂 快点帮我们松绑
Sorry... I forgot to tell you,
抱歉…忘记跟你们说了
but there's a slight change in our plan.
计划稍微做了点变动
Change?
变动？
After all, this is the only thing we got.
毕竟最后拿到手的就只有这个而已啊
So you guys can just die with the rest of them.
你们就跟那些人一起去死吧
What?
什么？
Since this shall be the end, let me tell you some good news.
我最后再告诉你一件好事
We'll take the cruiser parked near that bridge and leave.
我们会搭上停在那座桥附近的快艇远走高飞
Shortly after that, this airship will explode.
在那之后 飞行船就会爆炸
Starting from the cabin where the hostages are at.
从人质所在的客舱开始爆炸
I see. That's why you...
是吗 所以你才…
Since you defused the bombs which were placed at the fuel tank,
既然装在燃料箱的炸弹被你拆掉了
I had no choice but to set up two bombs in the cabin.
所以只好重新在客舱里面装上两枚了
Damn it!
可恶
But before that,
不过在那之前
I'll bury you in the bottom of the sea.
先让你葬身海底
Damn it, what should I do?
可恶 怎么办？
Is there a way... to turn the tables?
有没有…什么可以一举逆转颓势的方法呢？
I see it! It's the airship!
追上了 是飞行船
It's flying really low.
飞得还真低啊
If they continue their course...
继续这么飞的话
I know, they'll collide with the Akashi-Kaikyo Bridge!
对 会直接撞上明石跨海大桥啊
I can see the Kobe Tower and even the anchor sign of Mount Rokko!
可以看到神户灯塔呢 连六甲山的愤怒符号也有
Fantastic...
好棒…
Trying to distract me and make me bump my head against the bottom of the bridge?
你是想借此分散我的注意力 让我的头撞上桥底吗？
How could I fall for such childish trap?
我不可能上这种幼稚的当
What's going on?
怎么回事？
What happened?
怎么了啊？
Damn it!
可恶
How amazing!
好厉害
Just like a whale leaping out of the sea!
鲸鱼跃出水面了
Hello.
喂
Kudo, are you all right?
工藤 你没事吧？
Hattori, you phoned just in time.
服部 你电话来的正是时候
Call the maritime police now.
赶快联络海上保安厅
The maritime police?
联络海上保安厅？
The head of the organization fell into the sea.
首脑藤冈掉到海里去了
You said the criminal fell into the sea?
你说犯人掉到海里去了？
Also, their cruiser should be parked near the bridge.
还有 这群人同伙的快艇应该停靠在桥旁边
Please send some people to arrest them there.
那边逮捕他们的事就拜托你们了
Okay, I got it.
好 我知道了
See you later then.
那么待会见啦
I'll bring you to that Okonomiyaki place tomorrow. Look forward to it.
明天就带你去吃什锦烧 你就翘首以待吧
Hattori.
服部
Was that Kudo on the phone?
刚刚的电话是工藤吗？
Yeah...
是吧…
There's something I need to ask you.
我有事情想问你
Is Kudo... Kaitou Kid?
工藤他…是怪盗基德吗？
What?
啥？
Is everyone okay?
大家都没事吗？
Yeah, we are fine.
嗯 还好
We were just startled.
只是吓了一跳
Where are those guys?
那些家伙呢？
The two criminals over there passed out.
那边的两个犯人昏过去了
They hit the wall when the airship rotated.
刚刚飞行船竖起的时候撞到墙壁了
They can thank themselves for that.
真是自作自受啊
We are perfectly fine because we were tied up, huh?
我们这些被绑的人反而因祸得福了啊
Wow, this is such a surprise.
哎呀 真是让我吃惊啊
I had wanted to check the situation in the hall,
本来是想到大厅看看情况的
but the floor suddenly tilted.
没想到地板却突然倾斜
Kid, screw you!
基德 你这家伙
Kid sama!
基德大人
Where's Conan?
柯南呢？
That boy's fine.
那个小鬼他没事哦
He should be here soon.
应该马上就过来了吧
So please untie the rest of them.
那么就请你解开他们的绳子吧
Kid sama, please untie me!
基德大人 人家也要
Wait, Kid!
等一下 基德
Of course, please make sure this officer is the last one you untie.
当然 警官的绳子就拜托你最后再解开吧
Well everyone, as agreed, this jewel now belongs to me.
那么各位 依照约定 宝物我就笑纳了
Wait, you can't get away, Kid!
等一下 休想逃跑 基德
Damn you, you despicable thief!
可恶 你这可恨的小偷
Please call me 'Kaitou'.
请称我为“怪盗”
So the bombs were also...
那么炸弹也…
Okay, I see.
这样啊 我知道了
Thanks for your work.
辛苦了
The hostages are safe and the criminals were all captured.
所有人质平安 犯罪集团也被全数逮捕
We solved a big case.
总算是解决了一个大事件啊
Yeah...
是啊…
I'm so hungry!
肚子好饿啊
It's finally dinner time! I've been looking forward to this!
终于到了期待已久的晚餐时间了
Will there be grilled eel rice?
会不会有鳗鱼饭啊？
But, I feel like I've forgotten something.
可是 我感觉好像忘记了什么
Now that you've said that...
听你这么一说…
And now, it's time for your long awaited quiz!
接下来就是众所期待的猜谜时间
No one's looking forward to it.
又没有人在期待
Ayumi, Genta, and Mitsuhiko are all good kids.
步美 元太 光彦3个人都是很乖的孩子
Among the three of them, who's the most irrelevant to the airship?
这三个人之中 谁跟飞行船最没有关系呢？
That's it?
就只有这样而已啊
I can give a hint if you don't know...
如果不知道可以给提示…
The three of them are all related to it, right?
三个人都有关系吧
Note: Bad behavior(ひこう) sounds the same as flight in Japanese.
注：非行(ひこう)跟飞行同音
They are all good kids, so they don't misbehave.
就表示不会去做坏事(非行はしない)
And with Kansai accent, misbehaving sounds like airship.
而不做坏事可以说“非行せん”(关西腔)
Hikou (Airship).
所以ひこうせん(飞行船)嘛
That's what it is.
是这样啊
I see it now.
原来如此
If dealing with that thief would be as easy as the riddle,
如果对付那个小偷也能像猜这道迷题这么简单的话
I would've caught him easily and add a glorious chapter into my biography.
就可以轻轻松松地抓到他 在我的自传里再添一笔
Sister Sonoko,
园子姐姐
where's Sister Ran?
小兰姐姐呢？
Now that you've mentioned it, she's so slow.
这么说来 她还真慢啊
She told me to come over. I thought that she went to the restroom.
她叫我先过来 我还以为她去厕所了
Your girlfriend took the elevator to go up.
你那个女朋友刚刚搭电梯上去了
Maybe she went to find Kid?
会不会是去找基德呢
What?
什么？
So it's opaque.
果然不能透光啊
Shinichi.
新一
Crap, I forgot about that.
糟糕 我忘记这件事了
Hi, Ran.
嗨 小兰
What an exciting day.
今天真是刺激的一天啊
Shinichi!
新一
You have to turn yourself in!
快去自首吧 新一
Stealing is not the right thing to do!
当小偷果然还是不好
Please, Shinichi!
拜托你 新一
I understand.
我知道了
So...
那么…
If I can get the treasure I want the most from you, I'll turn myself in.
如果能从你身上得到我最想要的宝物 我就去找警方自首
But, I don't have anything.
可是 我什么都没有
That's of course...
那当然是…
W... Wait.
等…等一下
You are not Shinichi, right?
你不是新一吧
Conan!
柯南
Kid, you bastard!
基德 你这混蛋
That's right. I'm a thief, not a detective.
没错 我不是侦探而是小偷
A thief makes a living stealing other people's treasure,
小偷就是以窃取别人宝物为生
including an innocent girl's heart.
即使那是少女的纯情之心
Kid-sama is so handsome!
基德大人好帅啊
If he does that kind of thing to you, you won't find him handsome anymore.
他如果对你做出那种事 你就不会觉得他帅了
What kind of thing is that?
那种事是什么？
Lady Sky! Kid gave it back!
天空的贵妇人 基德把它还回来了
What did Kid do to you?
基德对你做了什么？
Something Shinichi would never do to me.
反正就是新一不会做的事
Why? Why wouldn't Shinichi do that?
为什么 为什么新一哥哥不会做呢？
Why do you think that?
为什么会这么觉得呢？
Because that's...
所以我说 那是…
I don't like him at all! Don't get me wrong!
我才不是因为喜欢他呢 不要搞错了
What?
什么状况？
Wait, Sister Ran!
等一下 小兰姐姐
What kind of thing... is that?
那种事情…到底是什么啊？